AARUUSH 2017 EVENTS REPORT 1: OUTLINE						
Objective: To grasp a general idea about the concepts on which the events are to be based and						
give a direction to the functioning of the domains henceforth.						
Directions for Filling the Report:						
-     Give an event wise description pertaining to the fields mentioned.						
-     Produce a pointwise and efficient report.						
-     Aim to give a general outline of each event with a round wise plan.						
-     Number of events to be proposed = 6 (minimum)						
EVENT: 4 stages						
INNOVATION/THEME:						
"Theme of this event is to depict the 4 - stages of life i.e school, college, work, and death. All the 4 rounds are based on the 4 stages of life."						
ABOUT THE EVENT: Detailed description of the Theme selected.						
This event is about the 4- stages of life and related memories with these 4 - stages. The motive of this event is to recall all the memories and depict all those memories in any expressive way.						
ROUND WISE OUTLINE/PLAN:						
Round 1(school life)						
"This round is about the school memories. In this participants will be given to write, draw about their best school memory."						
Round 2 (shipwreck)						
This round is related to college life. It tells about college life where you experience different emotions and how you deal with them. In this participants will be given two emotions and he has to choose any one of them and defend that emotion through his expression and speech.						
Round 3 (formal interview)						
This round is formal interview.In this round participant will be asked to prepare a CV and he will be interviewed by the faculty.						
Round 4 (last wish)						
In this round the participants will be given a choice to change 1 aspect of his/her life and then speak on it.						
Poem Presentation						
Everyone wants to become a great poet or writer so here we give you opportunity						
to present the poet in you						
Round 1:- English English everywhere						
For any poet he has to be good in that particular language so the 1st round is based on your English skills we will check out how well u know the synonyms and						
antonyms and use of popular phrase						
Judging criteria should at least answer 50% of the ques						
Round 2 :- time the rhyme						
For any good poem there must be the good rhyming sentences so here we give						
you few words and u have to build your own rhyming sentences						
Judging criteria how well they rhyme the sentences						
Round 3 poem writing round						
These will be the final round called as the poem writing round topics will be given						
to the those who clear the 1st and 2nd round and they have to write the poem on spot						
Judging criteria creativity ton the topic given spelling errors and use of theme						
properly						
Event -Break the Laws						
Round 1 defying the laws						
Participants will be provided with a set of laws; they have to frame a story such						
that it defies all the laws provided to them.						
Round 2						
"Depending on the story framed earlier, the participants will be asked to bring up"						
their own hypothesis and Write a paper supporting your hyp. (min. 2 pages)						
Round 3 Show it off!						
The participants selected for this round have to present their paper and will have						
clear the jury’s doubts( with supporting idea)						
Event name: Be the next Modi						
Round 1 elective manifesto						
Bring up your own manifesto which will prove you to be the next modi.						
Round 2 implementing strategy						
Pop up with ideas which will prove the strategy						
Round 3 bringing the tie						
Get your own worthy ideas to enhance the tie relationship between the						
neighbouring countries						
Round 4 the winning  speech						
The participants have to prove themselves worthy of being elected.						
Be the change						
Event 1: Greenovator						
"This event will test both your entrepreneur skills as well as your innovative thinking. The groups will be given 1 hour to come up with an eco-product which must be feasible and must be realistic. The product can be an idea or simply a material than can be used to reduce pollution and ensure ecological balance. They have to sell their product to the judges as well as to the students present in the panel. The cost/feasibility/quantity of the product will be decided by the teams and they have to convince the judges to buy their product. They have to explain why one should buy their product, how their product will save the environment, what changes it will cause to the present scenario etc. One member of the team has to explain about their product and the rest of the teams are allowed to ask questions."						
"Be the innovator and be the entrepreneur. If your idea is feasible, then it will be recommended to the Green Kalam project, a private undertaking aimed at saving the environment."						
Event 2: A Step Ahead						
"Complaint.. Complaints And Complaints.. Ever thought beyond this. What all does it take to solve a local problem. Get into the insights. Identify, Observe and solve your own local problems. We give you a chance to come up with your local issues and give your take on the same. See beyond complaining. Be the change you want to see."						
Round 3: Talk a thon						
"Participants will be given a social/environmental issue. They will have to engage in a healthy group discussion/debate to identify the issue, examine the present situation and steps to counter it. The teams will represent specific groups/organizations and will engage themselves into healthy debate putting forward their opinions/ideas."						
ACT IT OUT						
Round 1 Out of the box						
Each member will be asked a question but he should not answer related to the						
ques if he does the same he is out total number of question answered will be the winner e.g. if someone asks what is the day the participant should answer not related to ques						
Round 2 think smart						
A movie will be selected and the volunteer will act out the clue acc to the theme selected .e.g.						
Round 3 time for a change						
Give a different ending to a movie and it should be totally different						
Round 4 Monoact						
Act as a hero or villan acc to the movie which you choose						
EVENTS PLAN						
DOMAIN                             : Praesentatio						
ORGANIZER NAME        : Yash Tantia						
NAME OF THE EVENT   : Chanakya Neeti						
Concept of the Event (Theme and Field of Innovation the Event):						
Politics and policy making.						
Round wise description:						
ROUND 1:						
"    The participants will be given a picture.
    They will have to write an in-shorts article about it with a relevant headline."						
ROUND 2:						
"    Participants will be divided into groups and each group will be given a cabinet post.
    Each group will be given relevant study material according to the assigned cabinet post.
    Each will have to make a small speech on a topic related to their post and face questions."						
ROUND 3:						
"    From each group 2 participants will be selected. For ex, 1 will be given the post of finance minister and the other will be his deputy.
 A whole cabinet scenario will be created and the moderator will keep on introducing external factors within the discussion at regular intervals. This discussion will go on like a crisis meeting."						
AARUUSH 2017 EVENTS REPORT 1: OUTLINE						
EVENT 1: CORPORATE WORLD						
INNOVATION/THEME:						
"This eventexploits your creativity, marketing and manipulative and more importantly presentation skills at best."						
ABOUT THE EVENT: The event is 'Corporate World'. It is all about successfully launching a product and making it a hit among the masses. It even includes live merchandisingthe product which definitely utilises your presentation and Marketing skills.						
"The event has four rounds, each focusing onone stage of launching a product."						
ROUND WISE OUTLINE/PLAN:						
Round I : Screening						
"In this round, participant has to cook up a product and pen it down in as detailed manner as possible. The product can be as hypothetical an absurd as they like. The aim here is not to give ideas for a product but to show one’s creative and presentation skills. Example: Any where door."						
Round II : Blueprint						
"In this round, the participant has to picturisehis idea or give a rough draft."						
Round III : Visual Appeal						
This round focus on creating a hype about the product using electronic media. The participant has to create an AD/ MUTE AD about the product. He can use slogans or verses accordingly to create a buzz.						
Round IV: MERCHANDISING						
"This round focuses on putting the product in the market. In this, the participant promotes his product and defends it simultaneously. He also has to criticize other's product with genuine points."						
Time limit: Speaking - 4 mins						
Cross-questionnaire - 1 min.						
EDITOR’S PICK						
MAIN EVENT						
A youth magazine people need editors for their articles and so they hunt for young editors in a creative way... First they check the word proficiency of the guy by the spell bee.. So here whoever gets selected will go to next round... In the next round he will get a title of a famous book or famous story by the balloon shoot game... Then they must give a different ending to story or the book.. Here their imagination and creativity gets checked.. Then who wins will go for the next round that is group discussion... Here his ability is checked that what can his opinions be on current affairs and whether he is biased or non- biased.. Because an editor must be non- biased..... Then the final round is Editing And Editorial.. Here he will be given some information and he should present it in a proper article.. And then who wins the final round will become						
an editor with all the required qualities...						
ROUND-1						
" In the spell bee round, the contestants will be asked to spell a broad selection of words, with a varying degree of difficulty."						
 The individuals spelling the greatest number of words correctly will go on to the next round.						
 Each person will be given about 10-15 words.						
" This round checks the spelling efficiency and vocabulary of the contestant, two of the principle traits of the editor."						
 Example:- 1)cirrhosis						
2) Tendinitis						
3) Prospicience						
4) Autochthonous						
5) Logorrhoea						
6) euonym						
7) Vivisepulture						
8) Spoliator						
9) Elucubrate						
10) Esquamulose						
ROUND-2						
" In this round, the contestants will be given names of famous novels or movies, their job is to pick one and fabricate a different ending to the story."						
 This round tests the innovative and creative skills of the participants.						
 They will be judged on the basis of their imagination and creativity.						
 Example:- movies..1)harry potter						
2) Inception						
3) Interstellar						
4) DDLJ 5)3 IDIOTS						
NOVELS 1) Harry potter						
2) Five point someone						
3) I too had a love story						
ROUND-3  // TO BE CHANGED						
" In this round, the contestants will be divided into groups and each group will be given a topic for discussion. It is to see how they perceive things and also, comparing their answers to others."						
 The participants will have to put forward their opinion in a disciplined way.						
" This round checks their knowledge, confidence, communication skills, alertness and presence of mind, discipline."						
 Example:- 1) SOCIAL MEDIA						
2) SHOULD STREET ANIMALS BE REMOVED FROM SOCIETY						
3) SHOULD NIRBHAYA DOCUMENTARY BE BANNED IN INDIA						
ROUND-4						
 This is the ultimate round which involves performing the role of an						
editor.						
 It involves two steps – writing and editing.						
" The contestants will have to write an editorial, which is basically an article that expresses the views of an editor."						
" Then, their written works will be shuffled up and redistributed. Thus, they will have to edit the article written by another individual."						
" It is to evaluate the ideology, vocabulary, grammar, language, thinking, writing and editing skills."						
 Example:-						
// 10 Teams will be selected and divide into two teams where one team will be shown only video and other team member shud write and edit the news						
// newspaper preparing						
Back up rounds:-						
For round 1						
The backup for the first round is adzap- where the person has to come up with a new product and advertise it.						
Example:- nut and bolt						
For round 2						
The backup for the second round is						
dart board where the participant will be getting the topic of the famous movie or a book from the dart board game and then he has to exchange the roles of						
hero and the villain and narrate the story again.						
For round 3						
The backup for the third round is extempore where the participant will be getting the topic on the spot and he has to speak on it.						
But someone (any of the volunteers) will be there to ask him questions in between his extempore.. He has to answer them and also complete his extempore in the given time...						
Example:- generation gap						
2) Difference between burger and a wada (funny topic)						
For round 4						
There is no back up for the last round. Because this is the main and original						
round…						
Requirements:-						
1. Round 1						
"Sheets of paper, pens"						
2. Round 2						
"Balloons, cardboard for sticking the balloons on, toy gun for shooting the balloons, sheets of paper, pen"						
3. Round 3						
No basic requirement						
4. Round 4						
"sheets of paper, pens of different colours for the participants to write their editorials in a creative way."						
Members:-1)ayush(coordinator)						
2)chinmay(coordinator)						
3)anugna addula(co- coordinator) 4)lily priyadarshini(co-coordinator)						
Editors 2.0						
Round 1- The participants will be given articles to edit						
Round 2- cartoonscape						
Participants will be given any kind of message and they have to depict						
that message in form of a cartoon picture. Here the drawing skills will not be given the importance but the way they depict it will be.						
Example:-						
Round 3- Here the participants will be given a topic and they have to research on						
that topic and write an article.( suggestion make domains and let the participant decide )						
Round 4- Newspaper( suggestion: various year for different participants )						
In this round the participants will be asked to write a news paper in the						
proper layout with its name. They have to write about the news of the date given and also they have to include their cartoon scape and the research article in that						
newspaper too.						
EVENT 3:						
AARUUSH’16						
PRAESENTATIO						
"ROUND 1: In the first round, the participant is blindfolded and will be given few blocks in which"						
"each alphabet is carved, the participant has to touch and feel the alphabet to arrange them in"						
the given word form.If the word is not completed it would lead to direct elimination of the participant.						
"ROUND 2: The second round is based on story making where a puzzle is placed on a table, the"						
participant has to run to his/her allotted table and solve the puzzle to get the code on the puzzle. Participant has to decode the given code and then has to search for the decoded word from 5 chits placed in a bowl. The chit with the right answer contains a topic on which the participant has to write a short story. This task has to be completed in a particular time. The						
participant will be judged based on his/her story.						
"ROUND 3: In the third round, all the participants will be gathered together in a room and will be"						
asked to speak on a topic given by the other participants present in the room. The participant 1 will be asked to choose an alphabet on their choice and then select a random person from the participant who will give the participant 1 any topic of their choice which starts with the chosen						
"alphabet, Participant 1 has to speak on the topic given."						
"ROUND 4: Fourth round is based on debate, the participants will be divided into two groups and"						
a bottle is spun in between the two teams and the team at which the bottle stops will be given an advantage to choose a topic of their choice from the given topics and will be given an						
advantage to choose boon or bane to debate on.						
"ROUND 1:One word would have to be guessed by the participant with the help of 5 clues. Only one clue would be given in the starting and if the participant is not able to guess right, after some time, one more clue would be given. The more clues they use, the less would be their score.From the answer, they would have to derive more possible words. Repetition of letters allowed. For example-if the word is chemistry,"						
"they can get words like chemist,try,is etc.They have to get as many words as possible."						
Judging criteria :						
    the points will be awarded according to the number of clues used						
"    after the clue is given the participants can say the word only once , if that us wrong they have to move to next clue"						
    for making the words repetition is not allowed						
"ROUND 2: A line or two from a poem would be given to the participant.Now,he/she has to interpret what it can mean.They would have to explore as many meaningful interpretations as he/she can in a limited given time.It  could include positive,negative,philosophical etc.The people who write the most effective ones would be able to proceed to the next round. E.g hiku’s eg"						
An old silent pond...						
"A frog jumps into the pond, splash! Silence again."						
Autumn moonlight—						
a worm digs silently into the chestnut.						
Lightning flash—						
what I thought were faces are plumes of pampas grass						
judging criteria :						
    creativity of the participants as well as the number of interpretations will come in account						
"ROUND 3: In this round, the participants’ ability of expressing oneself would be tested by the way he/she writes.The participant would have to randomly choose a topic from some specific topics(like from a bowl or something). Now,he/she would be given a chance to select a genre using a dart and a board(he/she would have to aim at his/her preferred genre).Now,he/she would have to write a paragraph on the chosen topic in the specific chosen genre. For example-the word is biodiversity and genre is comedy,so now"						
he/she would have to be creative to write about this.						
"ROUND 4: 8 to 10 participants would be selected for this round.The participants would be given a controversial topic and they would be told to give 2-2 points for both against it and supporting it.Their points should not contradict their own points.If a participant finds its point proper to counter a person’s point,then he/she would speak but he/she would lose his/her one chance to speak.(ex-person speaks to counter in by taking against side,then he would have only one chance to speak against the topic).The ones"						
who would be speaking to the right points in a sophisticated manner would win.						
Events description						
1)  JAM Out Loud (JOL)						
"Prepare to duke it out with the rest of the competition to be declared the best orator. Speak for a minute, don’t let your rivals speak, object them for the mistakes"						
they commit and gain points for glory.						
Round 1: Amateurs: standard JAM rules apply.						
Round 2: Picture perfect: Interpret the image and get into the world of imagination.						
Round 3: Almost there! : A mixture of mutual dumb charades and brain teasers.						
Round 4: There! : a motley of cerebral and spontaneous and humorous skills makes						
you reach the zenith.						
2) Editors Pick						
Experience the enticing event on editing!!! Four rounds will acknowledge u to find out the reality of						
becoming an editor.  A good editor understands what you're talking and writing about and doesn't						
meddle too much.						
Round 1: names- 1) stellar spellar						
2) shower of words						
3)  spell down						
Round 2: names-1) chroma-twist						
2) cook-a-book						
3) dart your luck						
Round 3-names-1) race against time						
2) word power						
3) word management						
Round 4-names-1) critic review						
2) editorial brawl						
3) the editorial						
Youth Parliament (spl event)						
Ever wondered how it feels to be inside the parliament and put your views across? How it						
feels to be inside the parliament and make decisions that make an impact ?						
Presenting youth parliament .. an event which would simulate the actual working of the						
parliament. This event would provide excellent opportunity to students to express their ideas and views on policy making and at the same time make them aware the various issues that our nation is grappling with. It would also allow students to speak their minds without						
any inhibition while involving in a healthy debate.						
Round 1: talk the talk :Talk the talk is the first round. Here participants would have a group						
discussions on generic topics engaging in a brainstorming session. Each such moderated session would last for 10 minutes.						
"Round 2: Let’s debate : In this round, participants would involve in debating on issues"						
related to pressing issues that require the youth of the nation to have a say in.						
Round 3: The D-Day : The final round is the one where participants would involve in						
"engaging simulation of the indian Parliament, where participants would form the RULING side and OPPOSTION side and attempt to find the solution to the crisis at hand."						
THE DEFENDERS						
Are u a good defender with words then here is the event which will make u excited. The						
Defenders is an event where u can participate to find out how strong u are with words and with body language to make u feel like a politician or a reporter in the event.						
Round 1: Report the unpredictable: Be a spontaneous news reporter. One member will be						
the reporter and other is the cameraman who has to record the news delivery by phone or laptops given by us.						
"Round 2: think before you talk : Participate in the debate, but look where are you choosing."						
Do your task while debating.						
"Round 3: make them talk : Present the case as its yours. Time limit, adding twists and turns"						
bring the presentation to its best way possible.						
AARUUSH 2017 EVENTS REPORT 1: OUTLINE						
Objective: To grasp a general idea about the concepts on which the events are to be based and						
give a direction to the functioning of the domains henceforth.						
Directions for Filling the Report:						
-     Give an event wise description pertaining to the fields mentioned.						
-     Produce a pointwise and efficient report.						
-     Aim to give a general outline of each event with a round wise plan.						
-     Number of events to be proposed = 6 (minimum)						
EVENT 1:						
INNOVATION/THEME: EXPRESSO						
ABOUT THE EVENT: As the name suggests it’s about expressing oneself by different means.						
It checks out the overall view point of the participant towards seeing things.						
ROUND WISE OUTLINE/PLAN:						
Round 1:						
"The participant would be asked to select a random chit from a bowl. On the chit would be written the name of any object (eg. Sharpener, pen, fan, etc.). Now the participant, according  to the object on the chit, would have to express his/her life as that object in a specified amount of time like 30 seconds or a minute. The participant who is spontaneous enough and is able to talk without taking excessive time out gets promoted to the next round."						
"Eg.- Suppose the participant has to talk about a pen. He/she could start by talking about where he/she was made, what is he/she made of, who were his/her previous owners, any specific accident that might have happened to him/her in the past, etc. (The idea is to be spontaneous enough so that you’re able to talk for the specified amount of time)."						
Round 2:						
"5-6 random words or quotes would be given to the participant and using those words or quotes, they would have to make up an interesting story or a plot."						
"Now, after the participant has written his/her story, they will be asked to be a critic of their"						
"own story and thus, they will have to point out the loopholes in it."						
"Eg.- Suppose the participant has been given a quote “Live within your income, even if you have to borrow to do so”. Now the participant has to come up with an interesting story or a plot that is somewhat related to the quote, directly or indirectly. After writing the story or the plot, the participant would be asked to critically analyze their own story or plot and point out the loopholes in it."						
Round 3:						
"A half drawn painting will be given to the participant and the participant, using their own imaginative and creative skills would have to complete the drawing and give it a deep meaningful touch. The participant has to explain what the painting depicts either orally or by writing."						
"Eg.- Suppose the participant has been given a half drawn painting of a scenery. The participant then would have to draw the other half using his/her creative skills and give the painting a meaningful touch. It’s not necessary that the other half should be related to the scenery. In the end, the full painting should carry a meaning."						
Round 4:						
The participant would be shown a series of pictures relating to anything. He/she would then have to write a meaningful poem relating to the series of pictures and then decipher it.						
"Eg.- Suppose the participant is shown a series of 5 pictures that consists of a picture of a beautiful valley, a picture of a boy, a picture of a dog, a picture of a flower and a picture of a river. Now the participant has to link these pictures in a way so as to make a meaningful poem out of it. He/she would then have to decipher the poem."						
FANDOM						
"An event based on movies/books/TV episodes like Game of Thrones, Harry Potter etc. This is a"						
completely new idea for AAruush 2k16.						
This will be an event played in teams of 2.						
There will be a total of at least 5 options for the series out of which each team will have to choose 2.						
There will be 3 rounds.						
Round 1.1						
A trivia + activity based quiz round where each participant will be asked a set of questions while						
performing an activity say like juggling . In total 10 questions will be asked 1 point each.						
Failing to continue performing the task while answering a question will result in that point being lost.						
[There will not be any elimination after this round]						
Round 1.2						
An audio/blur visual/photo will						
be shown to the participant and will be given a short duration   of say 1 minute to write down his/her spontaneous imagination.						
[The total points of both the stages of this round will be calculated and the top selected participants						
will move on to the next level.]						
Round 2.1						
In this round the participants will have to work as a team em of 2.They will be asked to write a fan						
fiction having plots from both of their chosen series such that one person will write one line and the next would have to write the next line without discussion. The plot must not have more than 2						
"characters. They will be marked out of 10, 3 for"						
"originality, 2 for smoothness between the two combined story line, and 0 or 1 by a judge each out of"						
a panel of 5 judges.						
[The total number of teams moving forward will be reduced to half]						
Round 2.2						
The teams will be given a plot situation at random from their chosen series which they will be asked						
to enact in a funny way. Again they will be judged by a group of 5 judges each awarding either 0 or						
1						
point.						
[Only 10 teams will move forward to the final round]						
Round 3						
The QUEST round where the participants will be given riddles based upon their selected series and						
they will have to retrieve some objects. The fastest team wins.						
JAM Event Description in Detail						
7 to 8 speakers sit in a semi-circle and a topic would be given on the spot.						
Time is set for one minute and the first speaker to accomplish a given task gets the mike to speak. While this speaker (say speaker no 4) is speaking any of the other speakers can object by pressing a buzzer.						
The first person to object gets the mike provided his objection is correct and if it is correct he gets points for correct objection and gets the mike to speak. A wrong objection gets negative points. Every second a speaker talks he gets one point.						
"Objections can be made only restricting to these, or rather these are the RULES of JAM :"						
    Standard Formatting (or simply repetition) of a same word or idea more than 2 times.						
    Deviation from the topic						
    Hesitation (stammering or pausing unnecessarily while speaking)						
    Grammatical Mistakes (If the objection is write it Carries Maximum Points for the objector)						
"    Over-Dramatization (Putting too much of time in one word by extending it , like, “the wooooorrlld is an amaaaazing place…” etc. is against the law)"						
"    Wikipedia (Stating the obvious facts and wasting time, like “watches show the time..” etc."						
    Plagiarism (of another speaker’s idea in your speech is not allowed)						
    Incoherence (If the speaker isn’t audible to anyone. You can’t be incoherent)						
    Starting with a gerund (no sentences begin with a gerund “-ing” word)						
    Late start (starting too late after you’ve been asked to speak)						
    Jump the Gun (Starting even before you are asked to speak)						
    Speech-D (any Speech defects like tongue twisting etc..)						
"    Pre-Qualification (In India we go to….. “is wrong”; In the Country India we go to ….. “is right” , this is not just with countries, for example, Hrithik Roshan is a great at dancer “is wrong”, The actor Hrithik Roshan (or) The boy  Hrithik Roshan… is correct. If you bring any proper noun into your speech then you need to pre-qualify it.)"						
PRELIMS:						
"A batch has 8 speakers. Speakers are given Hilarious Topics that make you think and that plays with words, for example : “There was a bird named ‘Enza’ , I opened the window, and in-flew-enza (influenza) “, so it depends on how the speaker interprets the topic. The more creative and more hilarious he is more points they get. Some other funny topic may be like, “ I tried to eat the clock, but it was very time consuming”.  Normal JAM rules apply."						
QUARTER-FINALS :						
Pictures connecting to a proverb Example 1:						
This is : Don’t judge a book by its cover.						
The speaker who finds this out right gets extra points and he also gets the mike to speak.						
Example 2						
This proverb is “2 wrongs don’t make a right”						
Koofia						
Semi-Final :						
Has 2 exciting rounds.						
1st round (Dumb-C Glory)						
"In each round of the Semi-Finals there are set of 6 to 8 speakers in one batch. In each batch , speaker comes out one by one and he/she is given a Word to enact (the word can be anything a movie star, a book name, an author name, or a mathematic word like “polynomial” etc..). This speaker will be enacting this word to all the other speakers in that batch. The first speaker to guess that word correctly gets 10 points and the speaker who enacted gets 5 points. If no one is able to guess the word correctly then the speaker who is enacting gets -5 points."						
"Once the word has been discovered , the speaker who guessed it right will get the mike and start talking about that word. And standard JAM rules apply."						
2nd round (Disconnect)						
"A random speaker (say speaker2) is given the mike and he starts speaking randomly. No other speaker can speak or even have a connection to what speaker 2 has said. For example speaker 1 starts randomly by saying : “The blue color ribbon is…” and he gets objected for some correct reason by speaker5 , then neither speaker 5 nor any other speaker including spkr2 can speak about blue or ribbon. Objections can be made using 2nd degree connect , as in, if some spkr is talking about the sky then an objection saying that “the sky is blue and it was already mentioned by spkr2 “ is a correct objection.  The round goes interesting and makes all speakers , good listeners and shrewd."						
FINALS :						
"Has 1, 60 second rounds and 2, 30 second rounds."						
Round 1 (60 secs)           :						
1st 30 seconds   :						
"Questions or pictures or Connecting Pictures, relating to or leading to science as the answer would be posed. The first speaker to get the answer right gets the point and gets the mike."						
"For example,"						
"“Which branch of science deals with the identification of the substances of which matter is composed; the investigation of their properties and the ways in which they interact, combine, and change; and the use of these processes to form new substances?"						
It can also define the complex emotional or psychological interaction between two people.”						
The answer is just “CHEMISTRY”. If no one gets the answer options would be displayed :						
a)Psychology b)Electromagnetism c)Chemistry d)Physics						
"And the topic that arises from this answer would be,"						
"“Problems may prevail, but according to chemistry, Alcohol is a Solution.”"						
2nd 30 seconds  :						
Deals with solving basic math problems or mathematic questions like						
1.   March 14th is celebrated as              day in the US. In other parts of the world 22nd of July is celebrated as this same                 day. What is this day called?						
CLUE 1 : March 14 in the date form is 3-14 CLUE 2 : 22nd July is 22/7						
"The answer is Pi. (Clue will be given only if no one gets it in one minute). The topic that would be given for this answer is in a pic format like this,"						
i is not a real number and pi is not a rational number. The speaker who						
gets the answer as pi ly will get points and get mike to speak about the topic in this picture						
Round 2 (Tease your Brain [if you have one])     :						
This round has 4 to 5 brain teaser questions to which there is an answer and eventually this answer turns out to be the topic of this round.						
Example						
1.   Which month has 28 days?						
Ans) All months have 28 days.						
"2.   If you were running a race and you passed the person in the 2nd position, what position would"						
you be in now?						
Ans) 2nd position						
And the topics would be as abstract as “28 days” and “2nd position” . Abstract topics derive the best						
interpretation from speakers.						
Correct answer gets points wrong answer gets negatives						
Round 3 ( Screw your neighbor)              :						
Cross Word puzzles are given and the topic to talk is the answer itself.						
For Example :						
The question :						
The answer is						
And the final answer would be						
Once the topic has been revealed by finding out the answer usual JAM begins with the speaker who						
"found out the answer. This round is called Screw your Neighbor round and here, when a speaker (say spkr 5) is speaking, makes a mistake and if a speaker(say spkr1) objects , then the speaker sitting to his/her left (say skr2) has to make the objection. If the objection is correct spkr 1 gets +10 pts and spkr2 gets +5 points. If the objection is wrong spkr 1 gets -5 points and skpr2 get -10 points. And this becomes super fun as the game goes on."						
KOOFIAs						
The specialty of this JAM is that each round has its own koofias which are tasks to be performed while  speaking or before objecting. These would be:						
1.   PING round       : When you speak you say the word “ping” after every word you speak. For example : “I ping want ping to ping go ping to ping the ping school ping but ping…..” Speakers are bound to stammer or roll their tongues and objections can be made asap.						
"2.   Rhyme your Objection  : When you object you are supposed to rhyme . for example if the objection is that spkr2 stammered , then if someone objects they may rhyme like this,"						
"“I cut the wood with a hammer, I heard speaker 2 stammer”."						
3.   Crack a Joke before Objecting   : Before giving your objection you crack a joke and then only						
object. If the joke is good you get extra points.						
4.   Nursery Rhymes             : Before you object you say the 1st phrase of a nursery rhymes (say ‘twinkle twinkle little star’) and then object. When the next person objects he says the next phrase (‘how I wonder what you are’)and so on. After the last phrase you again come back to the first phrase. As the session goes on speakers tend to lose track of the phrase that they are supposed to sing. Wrong phrases gets you negatives. If spkr4 sings the wrong phrase then if spkr3 objects says the correct phrase spkr3 gets the plus points and spkr4 gets negatives.						
5.   Tell the name :  Before objecting you tell the name of a famous mathematician or scientist or						
astronaut or any famous person from the science background. If the spkr does not know any						
name or runs out of names or repeats the name he or someone else said earlier then he cant						
object and gets negatives.						
Note : If a speaker misses out on a koofia then other speakers may object to that and give the correct						
"koofia and fetch points. All these koofias would be mixed up in every round in quarter-final, semi-final  and final. It adds more alertness and thinking and fun to the event."						
Summary						
Total number of rounds = 4						
-> Preliminary round						
-> Quarter-Final						
-> Semi-Final						
-> Final						
"No.of participants expected for preliminary , minimum 150."						
"No.of Participants who would qualify for quarter-final = 80 No.of participants who would qualify for semi-final     = 35 No.of participants for finals                                                = 8 Winners = 1st ,2nd,3rd best Jammers."						
"Prelims and Quarter Finals would take place on one day, and the next day would have semi-final"						
and final.						
Duration :						
    Prelims 3 hours.						
    Quarter Final 3 hours.						
    Semi final 3 hours						
    Final 2 hours.						
Domain Name: PRAESENTATIO						
Event Name: LIT-TREAT						
Theme/Concept: This event focuses on how writing and literature						
"are involved in the technical world. Thus, engaging participants in a"						
very literary yet technical event.						
Round 1:						
Participants will be given a technology based crossword to complete within a stipulated time.						
Round 2:						
The words found by them in the previous round will be used by them to write a paragraph. Inclusion of all terms is mandatory for qualification to next round.						
Round 3:						
The participants are supposed to write a science fiction story which would be another story if read from backward.						
Round 4:						
Finalists will be provided with a technical taboo topic on which they have to give a 3 min speech.						
MISZILE						
Introduction						
"The event as the name implies is all about missiles. In this event, the guest lecturers"						
"would be giving a seminar on various equipments used in defense sector for instance: types of Missile, Missile drive, guidance system, war head, etc. After the seminar there would be a competition based on their presentation where the participants are required"						
to present their own ideas.						
Problem Statement						
The participants will be asked to present his/her ideas in the field of missiles or modern						
"warfare in their paper presentation. Based upon their way of presentation, Slides,"						
"communication, etc… they would be awarded points and the winner would be decided"						
accordingly.						
Event Description						
"The event would start with a seminar from the speaker, for about an hour. The seminar would consist of relevant photos, slides & videos. There will be 10 minutes time for queries, if any."						
There would be a break of around 15 minutes. After that the participants are allowed to present their papers. There would   be   2   winners   decided   depending   on          their						
performances.						
Rules and regulations						
1. The paper presented must be within the field of the topic of the event.						
2. A team could have a maximum of 2 members.						
3. The abstract should be in IEEE format.						
4. The presentation would be held only after the seminar ends.						
5. The winners would be decided by the judges only.						
6. The decision of the judges would be final and abiding.						
7. The coordinators are liable to change the rules in case of any discrepancy.						
8. Maximum time for presentation: 8 minutes						
9. Query by the judges: 1 minutes						
Frequently Asked Questions						
Q. What is the event about: a seminar or presentation?						
A. It comprises both of them. First there would be a seminar and then interested people may give a presentation on the topic of the event.						
Q. What would a participant get?						
A. A participant gets to know about missiles and gets a platform for paper presentation.						
Q. In which format should the abstract be?						
A. The abstract should be in IEEE format.						
Submission						
The participants can mail their abstracts to these email id’s						
pandeyjk3@gmail.com  kintalianish@gmail.com						
Judging Criteria						
The criteria of the selection of winners would be in judge’s discretion.						
Coordinators						
Jayant Kumar						
9791031689						
pandeyjk3@gmail.com						
K. Anish						
9677130802						
kintalianish@gmail.com						
Abhinav Saxena						
9940524538						
abhinavsaxena14@gmail.com						
MODINOMICS						
DOMAIN: PRAESENTAIO						
With the need of the time being great leaders to run the country and we know it’s in you. So bring it out						
and face the real time challenges a leader has to face before getting elected. Be ready to outcast your skills and be elected as the leader and the winner of the MODINOMICS						
ROUND 1: REASON IT OUT						
First let’s put a check on how high are you with the contents of a leader. A true ruler needs to						
be aware and able to solve problems on basic issues a country faces.						
So for a set of eight eligible candidates there will be questions on four major pillars of a						
country’s establishment.						
A)   National sector						
B)   International sector						
C)   Historical sector						
D)   National defense sector						
The participants will be shown a set of symbols drawn on the board. They have to choose one symbol.						
There will be four questions on four different categories. So behind each chit of question there will be one part of the symbol. They have to collect all the parts and complete the symbol but to get it granted						
they have to solve questions. If all questions are answered correctly then time will considered..						
JUDGEMENT CRITERIA: The accuracy and then the time will be considered.						
ROUND 2: GANGWAR						
The participants will be shown a case sheet of a constituency wid lots of problems.. And like it						
will will have constraints like population level population level and economy. And will have a set a problems in it. The objective is to prepare a solution to it taking care of the constraints and problem.						
They have to present it to the group of people.						
JUDGEMENT CRITERIA: The time will be considered. And also that all constraints are fulfilled.						
ROUND 3: PICTURE MANIA						
Just speaking is so not enough. It always requires manifestoes to capture minds and votes. The						
participants will be given a particular issue or situation. They have to prepare a manifestoes on it using softwares like Ronyasoft poster designer or adobe photoshop or simple paint. There will be a dartboard						
which will decide the issue on which you need to focus your manifesto on.						
JUDGEMENT CRITERIA: The partcipants will be judged on the effectiveness of the manifesto and then						
the time.						
ROUND 4: SPEAK IT OUT.						
"Narendra Modi, Adolf Hitler etc etc.. are said to great leaders and also as greatest orators of all time. So"						
its necessary to speak out your mind and convince the people to vote you.						
Participants will be given hot topics of present india. They will have to present a formal speech to attract						
the faculties and students who will judge and vote respectively for the most suitable leader.						
JUDGEMENT CRITERIA: How well you deliver your speech.						
EVENT 3: Skadoosh						
AARUUSH’16						
PRAESENTATIO						
"ROUND 1: In the first round, the participant is blindfolded and will be given few blocks in which each alphabet is carved, the"						
participant has to touch and feel the alphabet to arrange them in the given word form.If the word is not completed it would lead to direct elimination of the participant.						
"ROUND 2: The second round is based on story making where a puzzle is placed on a table, the participant has to run to his/her"						
allotted table and solve the puzzle to get the code on the puzzle. Participant has to decode the given code and then has to search for the decoded word from 5 chits placed in a bowl. The chit with the right answer contains a topic on which the participant has to write a short story. This task has to be completed in a particular time. The participant will be judged based on his/her story.						
"ROUND 3: In the third round, all the participants will be gathered together in a room and will be asked to speak on a topic given"						
"by the other participants present in the room. The participant 1 will be asked to choose an alphabet on their choice and then select a random person from the participant who will give the participant 1 any topic of their choice which starts with the chosen alphabet, Participant 1 has to speak on the topic given."						
"ROUND 4: Fourth round is based on debate, the participants will be divided into two groups and a bottle is spun in between the"						
two teams and the team at which the bottle stops will be given an advantage to choose a topic of their choice from the given topics and will be given an advantage to choose boon or bane to debate on.						
PICTURE PERFECT						
"This event draws a thread between fun activities, pictures and literary items. A fun"						
filled event containing four rounds.						
ROUND ONE:-						
The participants will be given two pictures.They will have to write one word out of the						
two given pictures. The one who is able to complete the more no. of pictures in a span of ten minutes will qualify for the next round.						
ROUND TWO:-						
The participants will be given a jar with a jigsaw puzzle of a picture. They will also be						
"given fifteen jumble words. As the participant is able to solve one jumble word, he or she will be allowed to take out one piece of the puzzle from the jar. Within a span of fifteen minutes whosoever is able to complete the whole task will be qualified for the next round."						
ROUND THREE:-						
They will have to throw a ring on the given bottles containing pictures. The one on						
which the ring stays will be the first picture. Then they are going to be given a riddle on solving which they will get a second picture. Now they will have to connect these two pictures and present a write up of about 300-400 words. Only 8 participants will move forward to the last round.						
ROUND FOUR:-						
Round four has two parts.						
4.1 :-						
The 8 participants will have to present a pictorial CV of themselves which will						
contain very less words and more of graphics. They will be judged on their ability to use pictures and depict their talents. 2 participants will be eliminated at the end of this round.						
4.2 :-						
The six finalists will have to present a ppt presentation  on a give social cause. They						
will have to use pictures mostly and make it as attractive as possible. They will be judged on the basis of their presentation skills and their intelligent usage of pictures to depict messages.						
Editors 2.0						
Round 1- Taboo.						
This is a team round. A participant will be given a word and related to this word 5 more words will be						
given. The participant has to make the other participant guess the word without using the 5 given words.						
Eg: Main Word- University						
"Related words- classroom, books, canteen, teachers, students"						
Round 2- cartoonscape						
Participants will be given any kind of message and they have to depict that message in form of						
a cartoon picture. Here the drawing skills will not be given the importance but the way they depict it will be.						
Example:-						
Round 3- Here the participants will be given a topic and they have to research on that topic and write an						
article.( suggestion make domains and let the participant decide )						
Round 4- Newspaper( suggestion: various year for different participants )						
In this round the participants will be asked to write a news paper in the proper layout with its						
name. They have to write about the news of the date given and also they have to include their cartoon scape and the research article in that newspaper too. Along with this they'll be provided with an article which they have to edit and also include in the newspaper.						
Event 1						
Domain praesentatio						
A worst case scenario will be provided and the participant is assumed to be candidate standing for						
students election in the campus and to select the student president he has to undergo various level of test so that the best candidate wins the seat .						
Round 1: problem analysis						
To be a good leader he has to analyze the problems happening in and around him. A pile of problem						
statements will be given and the participants have to describe how or what is the problem.						
Round 2: group discussion						
This round will be for why you want to dethrone the current leader and why were the problems						
aroused. Give your points March up the way.						
Round 3: election manifesto						
Studying the case and analyzing the situation given the candidate has to frame the election manifesto						
which should address all the problems. Candidates have to bring in strategies to implement the manifesto. He has to design an action plan by which he will bring in the changes and accordingly he has						
to frame a budget which will be approved by the management.						
Round 4:						
The candidate has to deliver a speech and the speech will be analyzed by faculties. In the last the voting						
will takes place where all the team members along with faculty will vote for the best candidate &he/she gets the post						
OLQ (Officer Like Qualities)						
Description:-						
"The event aims to give everyone a gist of Interviews they are going to face in their life. This event is a kind of Interview which has its rounds taken from India’s toughest interviews that are S.S.B and Civil Services. Each round will test participants personality, decision making skills and logical thinking, basically his/ her ‘’Officers like Qualities’’."						
Description of the 3 rounds:-						
The 3 rounds in our event are:-						
1)  Screening Round // INTERACTIVE ELEMENT TO BE ADDED						
2)  Psychological Test and GTO Round						
3)  Conference Round						
Screening Round:-						
"The participants will be given circumstances and situations where they need to showcase their “presence of mind”, intelligence, thought processing and decision making skills."						
Events in this stage are:-						
1) Picture Perception and Deception Test (PPDT).						
2) Making Sentences.						
"Under the PPDT, participants will be given a hazy picture based on which they have to think and discuss their opinions with the judges. Time given to each participant is 3 minutes."						
"Example, Participants will be given a hazy picture of blood on the ground. Those participants who write points like the blood came there from an accident which had taken place previously, will be considered as negative points. Participants who write the that the blood had come from the hands of a tennis player who had been rallying for hours together, thus displaying his"						
"tenacity and dedication, will be considered as positive points. Each participant"						
has to come on stage and justify his/her story. The discussion will be open for						
counter questions.						
"For the second round, each participant will get 5 words based on which they must form a sentence. Time limit for each participant is 2 minutes."						
Marks will be given based on the thought process and creativity in both the rounds.						
Participants will be Shortlisted on the basis of this round.						
Psychological Round						
"•   This round will test the participant’s ability to handle stress, presence of mind and decision making skills which are an integral part of an officer."						
•   It will consist of 3 rounds:-						
1) Word Meanings						
2)Situation Response Test(SRT) 3)Self Description.						
Rules:-						
•   The “Making Sentence” task will require the participant to make sentences out of 30 words in a rapid fire round. Each word will be given a time limit of 15 seconds. This competition is designed to induced stress and will test the participant’s ability to handle it.						
•   Situation Response Test(SRT) will test the participant’s decision making skills. 3 situations will be given to the participants and they will have to assess the situation and think of a suitable response to handle it. Time limit for each situation is 5 minutes.						
"•   In the “Self Description” round, the participant will have to describe about himself/herself and what his close associates think of him/her. Time limit for this event is 7min."						
•   Group Testing Round						
•   The qualifying participants will be competing in the group testing stage. This round has two stages:-						
•         1) Group Discussion						
•         2) Group Planning Exercise						
•   The no. of students selected will be divided into batches of 5-6 for this						
round.						
"•   In the Group Discussion, participants will be given a topic related to social issues or abstract ideas. Time limit for this event is 10min."						
"•    In the Group Planning Event, each team will be given a particular situation which they have to assess and complete in the stipulated time"						
as a team.						
Conference Round						
"•   Finally, the 5-6 participants selected after the above rounds will have a personal interview with all the judges."						
•   He will be judged based on the answers he gives to the interviewers.						
"•   This round will test the candidate’s personality, whether he has the"						
“OLQ”.						
Event						
The Debaters						
Domain						
Praesentatio						
Introduction						
"“I love argument, I love debate. I don’t expect anyone just to sit back and agree with me, that’s not their job”-"						
If this is what you believe then this time we have come with the most unique and promising event for every debater						
who loves to debate.						
Detailed Description						
1.    This event will consist of four rounds.						
"2.    The first round is the “Brain Storm” round where a set of 50 MCQ type questions will be given. The questions will be based on the theme of sustainability, environment and green technology."						
3.    The second round is the “Speech Jammer” round. In this round the team will be divided as 1 for favor and 1 for against. At the end the total points for a team will be calculated. This round is a type of extempore where one out of the two participants for a team will be given a topic to speak first. He will be interrupted at any point of time and the other speaker will be asked to continue the idea from there.						
4.    The third round is the “Audio-Visual” round. Here the participants will be shown a maximum of 8 video clips. The clips are going to be related to green technology and sustainability. The participants will be given 2 minutes for each video to pen down a synopsis on the basis of their observation.						
"5.    The final round is going to be “The Debate” round. 5 problem issues regarding environment and sustainability will be discussed. Each topic will be debated by two teams (one proposition-one opposition). This round will be consisting of speakers, judges and the jury. Jury will comprise of the participants who got eliminated in the 3rd round. Voting shall be done by the jury by raising placards (Green for proposition-Red for opposition) for the team which spoke the best"						
"according to them, for each topic that will be discussed."						
Other Details						
1.   Rules and Regulations						
1.1.  Each team consists of 2 participants.						
1.2.  Participants are not allowed to use any kind of electronic gadgets during debate round.						
1.3.  Negative marking will be considered for 1st round MCQ type questions.						
1.4.  Final decision taken by the judges and the event coordinators will be final and binding.						
2.   Judging Criteria If Any						
2.1.  Judging Criteria for 1st round: Max no. of correct questions attempted.						
"2.2.  Judging Criteria for 2nd round: The participants will be judged on the basis of the fluency, expression and ideas put forward by them. Team coordination will count for their selection to next round."						
2.3.  Judging Criteria for 3rd round: The participants will be judged on the basis of the no. of videos they have covered						
and the content of the summary they write. The judges will already have predefined set of answers. Teams with most appropriate keywords in their summary will be taken to the final debate round.						
2.4.  Judging Criteria for 4th round: Marks will be allotted to the speakers on the basis of-						
2.4.1. Reasoning & Evidence						
2.4.2. Organization & Prioritization						
2.4.3. Listening & Response						
2.4.4. Expression & Delivery						
2.4.5. The jury vote will be counted as a jury point that will be added upto the team points.						
2.4.6. In case of a tie 2 questions from the jury (one for proposition-one for opposition) will be entertained to which another point will get added to the team.						
FAQ						
1.    What kind of topics can be expected during “Speech Jammer” round?						
"Topics will be solely based on sustainability, environment and green technology."						
2.    Minimum Number of Participants						
2						
3.    Maximum Number of Participants						
2						
4.    What would be the Event Venue ?						
Would be Announced on our website http://www.aaruush.net						
5.    What is sustainability?						
"Sustainability is the capacity to endure. For humans, sustainability is the long-term maintenance of responsibility, which has environmental, economic, and social dimensions, and encompasses the concept of stewardship, the responsible management of resource use."						
6.    Will there be prizes for the jury?						
"Only the winner and the 1st runner up will be awarded with cash prizes and certificates. Jury will awarded with special goodies and certificates. Special prizes will be awarded for the best individual speaker, best jury"						
7.    What if my partner is not a good debater?						
You will lose points as a team. The team will be judged as a whole. There will be a special award for the best individual speaker.						
Contact:						
Joyee Sarkar						
Mb : +91 9790919174						
Email : joyee.winner@gmail.com						
Sakshi Arora						
Mb : +91 9176372097						
Email : sakshi.arora0415@gmail.com						
Shashank Jain						
Mb : +91 9677051835						
Email : shashankjain@srmuniv.edu.in						
PICTURE PERFECT						
"This event draws a thread between fun activities, pictures and literary"						
items. A fun filled event containing four rounds.						
ROUND ONE						
The participants will be given two pictures. They will have to write one word out of the two given pictures. The one who is able to complete the more number of pictures within a time span of ten minutes will qualify for the next round.						
ROUND TWO						
The participants will be given five riddles. On solving each riddle they will get a picture. They will have to solve five such riddles and hence get the five pictures. They will then have to correlate these pictures to one basic point. They will have to further write it down on a piece of paper explaining the connection between all the five						
pictures.						
ROUND THREE						
"The participants will b given a jar with a jigsaw puzzle of a picture. They will also be given fifteen jumble words. As the participant is able to solve one jumble word, he/she will be allowed to take out one piece of the puzzle from the jar. Within a time span of fifteen to twenty minutes whosoever is able to complete the whole task will be qualified for the last and final round."						
ROUND FOUR						
In this round the participant has to complete 4 steps.						
In the phase one they will have to throw a ring on the given bottles						
containing pictures. The one on which the puzzle stays will be the first picture that they will get.						
In the phase two they will have to throw ping pong balls into the						
numbered cups. Whichever cup they are able to put the ball in will help them get a picture assigned to the number on the cup.						
In the third phase they will have to make a castle out of ten cups in						
thirty second. The more time they take the lower will be their score and hence with the accordance to their scores they will receive a						
third picture.						
In the fourth and final phase the participants will have to correlate						
these pictures and put a write up in about 600-800 words.						
Domain Name: PRAESENTATIO						
Event Name: Pitch Perfect						
"Theme/Concept: In today’s world, pitching is the most important"						
"quality a man can have. If you can’t sell it, you can’t buy it. This event"						
revolves around how a product is built from scratch and delivered to the audience. Show us if you can pitch the product perfectly!						
Round 1:						
It is a round for those who have the ability to cast a spell on buyers.						
"If you have the innovative bent, power of packaging and presentation, then we challenge your imagination to think big and think new."						
Round 2:						
"If the previous round was your cup of tea, this round will be a can of worms for you. You have to think of a product which has never been thought before, the impossible!"						
"Your work isn’t done yet! Now, draft its blueprint and state its applications."						
Round 3:						
Your product is almost ready but on paper! We challenge you to make it a reality. And the biggest hurdle in that is getting it approved by the higher authorities.						
"We challenge you to get it passed because if you do, you might have the chance to win!"						
Round 4:						
The final round judges your pitching skills. Pitching it to the authorities might be easy but what if you have an actual customer to pitch for?						
Pitch it fastest and grab the prize of Pitch Perfect fastest!						
