MAIN EVENTS-										
Clash of cells										
Event 1										
Everyone fights their own so does our body. Our body has its own system to fight against the enemies in										
this event come let’s check how much knowledge you have about your body.										
Round1:										
round in relation to the concept of school contest.										
Round 2:										
Various images related to immunity will be projected on screen you have to identify what it is. The most										
you identify the higher you can defend tour place for the next round.										
Round 3:										
Few bacteria virus and some other microorganism will be your opponent team. You have to defend your										
"own body. We provide you with antibodies, and few immune stimulating complexes and few helper cells. All you have to do is develop a strategy (only one strategy is correct) and the one giving that wins"										
the game.										
CHEMOFLAUGE										
Event 2										
Chemicals are used in our everyday life but no one knows what to use and when to use										
Round 1 chemical housie										
"Well if u thought it was a cup of tea for you then wait for the twist, the uses of chemical ( elements"										
from 1-40) will be given and an element number will be called out in random participants have to play housie as well as match the number with the										
Round 2										
Everyone would have surely seen an ad for soap or shampoo but have u seen an ad for a chemical . so										
create your own ad for the set of chemicals provided and sell it to the company										
Round 3 chemical monopoly										
An exact setup like that of monopoly will be set up but there is a twist we don’t provide you with money										
instead we give u chemicals and few industries where this chemicals will be required so march up your way and show us u have got the talent to reach the top										
Round 4										
Well what you thought all this was fun then wait now we know that you have got talent chemically we										
"will give you an industry which has lost all the profit because of the mistakes in the chemical setup or chemical reaction or probably a wrong reactant , we will give u a case study about the industry and time"										
to solve it out . the best contestant wins .										
DEATHLYMELODY										
Event 3										
People fall ill all the time wouldn’t it be fun if you don’t have to go the doctor and diagnose										
yourself or your friends. Let’s see how good you are in diagnosing.										
Round 1										
Participants will be given simple questions related to different types of disease and disease										
"causing germs. example- different types of bacteria, virus, fungi, etc. (objective type)."										
Round 2										
"Participants will be given different elements of the living organisms, which will be associated to"										
"different things .They have to find the name of the thing, to get the next clue. With every clue they will be given a symptom from all the symptoms they have to guess the correct disease which shows those symptoms."										
Round 3										
Participants will be shown a video or PPT and they will be asked to memorise the important										
"information about the organisms shown, which will help them to solve the problem given later."										
"After showing them the video, participants will be asked to use the DNA of the different"										
"organism show in the video, to form a virtual human which will be immune to the given diseases and certain sets of conditions (they have to write the reason for choosing the particular organism)."										
Round 4										
Before we can find cure for any disease it is very important to diagnose it correctly. The										
"participants will be given a patient showing various symptoms (of an incurable disease), with the help of those symptoms and the setup of his house or work place the participants have to"										
diagnose the disease and find a cure by testing the different objects given in the setup.										
SENSOLOGY 2.0										
Round!) 1 (shake free shake)										
This round is divided into two parts										
1st part										
"In first part, any one of participates will be given a beat or music to remember, after his partner"										
"completes the 2nd round, he will be given 4 to 5 different samples of sound from which he have to identify the one he heard in the beginning."										
2nd part										
"In this part participant will be given three different samples of milk shake (10 ml each), which"										
he have to identify from a list carrying names of different shakes with his nose closed										
(deception of taste).										
Round 2 (multitasking! can you?)										
Participants will be asked very simple bio related questions (rapid fire) with a twist. The twist is										
that they will be performing a physical task (example- balancing something or themselves) and while performing the task they have to answer the questions.										
Round 3 (one out of 4 eye!)										
Participants have to perform a task of dropping some objects in the bowls kept in front of										
"them, but the participant who will drop the objects would have his eyes closed and his partner with the use of one eye only have to guide him (creating deception of 3D viewing). The first participant also have to pic particular objects (which has to be dropped in the bowl) from many"										
different objects present (just by feeling the objects).										
Round 4 (game parlour)										
"Participants will be asked to find a coin from a box filled with ice cold water, for each coin they"										
"find they will be given a question to answer related to interesting biology or chemistry, the team which answer the maximum no. of question within 5 min will win the round."										
PRAESENTATIO-PAPER PRESENTATION TOPICS										
SCHOOL OF COMPUTER SCIENCE										
1.   4g Wireless Technology										
2.   Computational Neuroscience and its advancements										
3.   E-wallet										
4.   Facial recognition system and Biometrics										
5.   Knowledge Engineering and Natural language processing.										
6.   Body sensor networks										
Coordinator – Vineeth D										
9894928593										
BTech Pre-Final Year Computer Science Engineering										
                                                         comp.aaruush2012@gmail.com                                                          										
SCHOOL OF Electrical & ELECTRONICS										
1.   MIMO OFDM										
2.   Distributed Generation Systems										
3.   E BOMBS										
4.   Energy Efficient Machines and its controllers										
5.   Solutions to Spectrum Congestion Problems										
6.   Claytronics and Its Applications.										
 7.   Microphotonics In Fiber-optic communication                                                                              										
Coordinator – Suchitra Jena 8939017979										
BTech Pre-Final Year										
Electronics and Communication Engineering elec.aaruush12@gmail.com										
SCHOOL OF MECHANICAL										
1.   Micro air vehicles										
2.   Alternative fuel usage in automobiles										
3.   Creation of auto-bots as a replacement of still machines										
4.   Space mining and its applications										
5.   floating solar power station										
6.   inter orbital settlement										
Coordinator – Shruti Bandyopadhyaya										
9003029788										
BTech Final Year Aerospace Engineering										
                                                           mech.aaruush12@gmail.com                                                            										
SCHOOL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY										
1.   Synthetic biology										
2.   Cancer-fighting it with inhibitors of angiogenesis										
3.   Gene Therapy-methods and prospects and recent advances										
4.   Bio Fermentation										
5.   Nano-medicines										
6.   Intelligent food protein analyzing systems										
7.   Wearable Bio Sensors										
Coordinator – Shounak Paul										
9445431753										
BTech Pre-Final Year Biotechnology Engineering										
                                                             bio.aaruush12@gmail.com                                                              										
SCHOOL OF CIVIL ENGINEERING										
1.   Soil Stabilisation										
2.   Sustainable transport systems										
3.   Corrosion resistant Structures										
4.   Application of GIS and Software packages in Civil Engineering										
5.   Solid Waste Reduction-Harbinger of a Sustainable Society										
6.   Nanotechnology in Civil Engineering										
Coordinator – Lantav Jain										
8939013979										
BTech Pre-Final Year Civil Engineering										
                                                            civil.aaruush12@gmail.com                                                             										
Rules and Regulations										
1. Both Author and Co-author must be bona fide students of a University/College.										
2. The registration for the paper will be done on the day of event in case the paper reaches the final presentation										
"stage. Both the participants have to register for the event. Even if one of the authors is not able to attend the presentation, the other has to register on his behalf."										
3. There are no registrations required to be done during abstract and full paper submission stage.										
"4. Certificates will be issued only to those participants, who have presented their paper in the final round and also"										
have registered for the event.										
4. Prizes will be given to the top two best paper presentations based on the criteria decided by the judges.										
5. Submit the abstract in standard format given on the website. It should be limited to a page.										
6. Only one abstract per author is permitted.										
7. Mail your abstracts to the respective mail Ids provided along with the Schools of Engineering on or										
before 16/08/2012.										
8. You are required to MENTION ‘THE NAME OF THE TOPIC’ in the subject of your mail. Also your attachment										
file should be saved as the name as your topic and nothing else.										
"9. Mention Your Name, Year, Course, College/University, Phone Number and Mail ID both in the mail and the"										
attachment file.										
10. Intimation about the selection of paper will be given through mail latest by 19/08/2012.										
11. Selected participants have to mail their full length papers to the respective email address.										
12. The full length papers must be submitted in IEEE format and should not exceed 6 pages.										
13. Decision of judges shall be final and it will be binding to all.										
14. If a participant does not follow any of the rules his/her paper will be disqualified. For further details mail your										
enquiry at praesentatio@aaruush.net.										
Important Dates										
16/08/2012—Last date for abstract submission										
19/08/2012—Intimation of selected participants										
28/08/2012—Last date for full paper submission										
01/09/2012—Intimation of selected participants for the final presentation round										
PROJECT    DOCUMENTATION-AIML										
GROUP-2										
PROJECT NAME:										
HEAD 1:										
HEAD 2:										
HEAD 3:										
MEMBER 1:										
MEMBER 2:										
MEMBER 3:										
MEMBER 4:										
ABSTRACT										
INTRODUCTION INSPIRATION WHAT IT DOES LIMITATIONS BENEFITS										
EXECUTIVE SUMMARY										
REQUIREMENTS										
    Libraries used										
    Frameworks used										
    Dataset details										
    Other requirements (if any)										
PROJECT SCHEDULE										
INDEX										
Module	Activity	Subtask	Assignee	Planned start date	Planned end date	Actual start date	Actual end date	Status		
IMPLEMENTATION DETAILS										
    Codes and their explanation										
SCREEN SHOTS OF THE WORKING MODEL TESTS REPORTS										
    Performance of training set										
    Performance of test set										
    Overall accuracy of the model										
CHALLENGES FACED ACCOMPLISHMENTS WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNT? GITHUB REPO										
RESOUCES										
EVENT 1 :										
Innovation and theme : Sarcasm										
About the event :										
"Sarcasm is a remark made mockingly, ironically, or in bitter contempt so as"										
"to show some foolishness on the part of the interlocutor. The speaker’s vocal or physical cues are usually necessary to signal the sarcasm, such as accompanying a statement by rolling one’s eyes or speaking with a specific tone. Sarcasm examples often employ irony though this is not a requirement. Situations can be ironic, but only some people can be sarcastic."										
This helps an individual discover and evolve a new way to present their selves and tackle situations by playing witty.										
"Praesentatio brings to all, this boisterous and amusing event."										
Description of rounds:										
Round 1 –Shaping the shaped										
Here the participants would be made to hear the Bollywood and Hollywood dialogues being played. These dialogues will be the ones with very serious tone and situation. The participants are supposed to edit the dialogues and add sarcasm to it and speak it with their choice of tone and manner. The facial expressions and the body language of the participant would be kept										
in mind during judgement.										
Round 2 –Meme – esmerising										
The participants would be shown sample memes. They have to take ideas from those and make their own memes. Their creativity and expression skills would be kept in mind.										
Round 3 –Sarcaso – jocking										
Here the participants are supposed to have a conversation with an										
"assigned person from the team who would counter back the participant with statements and it would kind of depict a rapid fire scenario , difference being that the participant is supposed to maintain his sarcastic tone as well as he is supposed to be confident during the entire"										
conversation.										
Round 4 –Mocking the herd										
Here the participant is supposed to prepare a satirical speech and recite it in a sarcastic tone. They are supposed to give their level best performance as an individual speaker and also since this is the last round we would keep in mind that the speaker’s sarcasm level doesn’t fall down from the										
previous rounds and also that originality must be maintained.										
Short Film Making										
"Have a flair for film direction, acting, cinematography or editing? This is a great opportunity"										
for you.										
"Short Film Making is an endeavour to encourage budding film makers all over the country, to"										
"showcase their talent, and compete with some of the best in their cadre. Whether you want to have fun, get recognition, or cap jaw-dropping prize money, Short Film Making will leave you with an experience you wouldn’t forget."										
So get those cameras rolling!										
Important Dates										
Deadline for sending in entries for prelims: 1st September										
Announcing of Shortlisted of teams           : 5th September										
Event Description										
The teams will be short listed based on the video they submit. The winners will be announced										
prior to commencement of Aaruush. Videos of the best entries will be showcased during Aaruush.										
"The entries should reach us by midnight of 1st September, 11 either through emailing a copy of your film to sfilms.aaruush@gmail.com or emailing us the link of your video"										
on Youtube or any other such web portal.										
"Mail us your details(Name, College, College ID number along with your Aaruush ID). THE"										
TEAM MEMBERS NEED NOT BE FROM SAME COLLEGE.										
Themes -										
     Social Message										
     Documentary										
     Thriller										
     Comedy										
(Please refrain from making animation films in this competition)										
Rules And Regulations										
The maximum number of members in a team cannot be more than 10. The runtime for films should not exceed 10 minutes.										
"Please avoid obscenity, pornography, excessive violence, and photo slideshows (USE OF PROFESSIONAL HELP IS PROHIBITED FOR ANY PART OF THE FILM MAKING)"										
Films in languages apart from English should be accompanied with subtitles. In your own interest please make sure that the subtitles are visible against the background throughout the film.										
"Please refrain from making advertisements, remixes and spoofs."										
A letter of authentication for your film is welcome from any authorized personnel from your institute with their seal and signature.										
Co-ordinators										
For further queries contact any of the following coordinators										
NAVEEN KUMAR.R                 +919884224184										
FAQ’S										
1. Can students from different colleges form a team?										
Ans: Yes students from different colleges can form a team and participate.										
2. Will we have to do registration for participating in the event?										
Ans: Yes all the team members must first register on our website and then only send the										
entries.										
3. where do we need to submit the entries?										
Ans: All the entries must reach sfilms.aaruush@gmail.com by 1st of September.										
"If you find that something’s missing, you can always ask: praesentatio@aaruush.net"										
EVENTS PLAN										
DOMAIN                             : Praesentatio										
ORGANIZER NAME        : Yash Tantia										
NAME OF THE EVENT   : Sinful Satire										
Concept of the Event (Theme and Field of Innovation the Event):										
This event takes a comic look towards the various day to day things in life and various social issues.										
Round wise description:										
ROUND 1:										
"The participants will be required to make their own Micro Tales with comical twist in the end.
Ex:
She kept on begging him but he showed her no mercy. As she cried...
....he gave her another spoiler."										
ROUND 2:										
"    The participants will be given a ppt prepared by us in advance.
    He won’t be allowed to look at it before he goes on stage to make his presentation.
    A lot of off topic and silly phrases will be included in the ppt.
    The participants will be required to make the presentation with a straight face, explaining everything in the ppt and giving logical reasons as to why that phrase/image is related to his presentation."										
ROUND 3:										
"    This round will be placed as a faceoff between 2 participants.
    A stupid court case will be created and the participants will be required to fight it without worrying about the stupidity of the case.
Ex: The Modi Snap filter case."										
ROUND 4:										
A serious social topic will be given to the participants. They will have to make a very sarcastic/satirical speech. Even though the audience might laugh the whole speech should force then to think about the topic on a deeper level.										
SPECIAL NOTE (if any):										
EVENTS PLAN										
DOMAIN                             : Praesentatio										
ORGANIZER NAME        : Yash Tantia										
NAME OF THE EVENT   : Social Network (Proper name yet to be decided)										
Concept of the Event (Theme and Field of Innovation the Event):										
This events aims at exploring the fun of social networking.										
Round wise description:										
ROUND 1: Caption It										
The participants will be given 3-4 images and they will be required to caption them using at max 140 characters.										
ROUND 2: SnapFilter										
"The participants will be making an innovative filter and taking a picture with it.
They will be provided with papers and art supplies. They will have to make props of the filters they want to make."										
ROUND 3: 30 secs to fame										
The participants must make a 30secs to fame videos. The videos can be of any theme.										
ROUND 4: Photography										
"The participants must give an entry of 10 pictures depicting life in SRM and Potheri based on the themes given to them,"										
SPECIAL NOTE (if any):										
AARUUSH 2017 EVENTS REPORT 1: OUTLINE										
Objective: To grasp a general idea about the concepts on which the events are to be based and										
give a direction to the functioning of the domains henceforth.										
Directions for Filling the Report:										
-     Give an event wise description pertaining to the fields mentioned.										
-     Produce a pointwise and efficient report.										
-     Aim to give a general outline of each event with a round wise plan.										
-     Number of events to be proposed = 6 (minimum)										
EVENT 1:										
INNOVATION/THEME: Social Network.										
ABOUT THE EVENT: This events aims at exploring the fun of social networking.										
ROUND WISE OUTLINE/PLAN:										
Round 1- The participants will be given 3-4 images and they will be required to caption them using at max 140 characters.										
Round 2- The participants will be given 5 random emojis and they will be required to make a story out of it.										
Round 3- The participants must make a 30secs to fame videos. The videos can be of any theme. The participants will be divided into teams of 2 randomly.										
Round 4- The participants must give a entry of 10 pictures depicting life in SRM and Potheri and justify their photos.										
SPARK TALK										
DESCRIPTION:										
An TED Talk-format based event that gives innovative and creative enthusiastic										
"college students a wide platform via YouTube viewership and listener crowd at the fest to pitch up their path breaking idea to a real audience, tells the feasibility of the idea and its popularity gathering. The event will have students as the speakers with their own idea to pitch up to the audience with video, power point presentation, paper presentation, white board round etc. in order"										
Round 1: The questionnaire form fill up round and paper presentation round. (4 hours)										
Round 2: The “Pitch your video round”. 2 minute video that describes the idea										
and basically markets it. (3hrs)										
Round 3: The “PPT Show round”. (3hrs) (9 slides max)										
Round 3: The “White Board Round”. (2hrs) (5 minutes to present)										
Round 5: (FINAL ROUND): “DELIVER THE TALK”. (4- participants/participating										
team only). (1 hr)										
"Every round filters the participants on the basis of the authenticity, creativity,"										
"genuinely innovation, uniqueness and the way of presentation with constraints put in."										
to influence the crowd listening to the talk also an opportunity to cross										
question the other speakers from crowd as well as fellow speakers. Judge’s scores and spectator vote will account for the winner’s score.										
THE DEFENDERS										
Round 1: Report the unpredictable										
Videos/backdrops/poster will keep on changing by our volunteers so will the news										
"you have to report. Be a spontaneous news reporter. One member will be the reporter and other be the cameraman who has to record the news delivery by phone or laptops given by us. Now recording the event is also an art i.e timing when to focus on news reader and when to focus on changing images/poster at the back. Now these recordings will be given to our judges for evaluation for the backdrops/poster there will be 3 criteria politics,entertaintment,weather and total 6 posters/backdrops i.e both one easy and one difficult poster per criteria.Eg;:- entertainment poster of1 EASY- sharukh khan fighting guards of stadium 2 Poster of exclusively shilpa Shetty ,now the contestant will be confused whether it about her next movie or IPL scam.Accordingly they have to think fast as clock is ticking and posters/backdrops are changing quite fast&and all the 6"										
posters are shuffled they are not in order or criteria wise.										
"Judging criteria: Spontaneous thinking, fast switching."										
"Requirements: Cardboard /thermocol sheets (24, for backdrop), Laptops, Fevicol"										
"(4), Posters."										
Place: Classrooms (2)										
The reporters are on a news channel “towards infinity”										
Round 2: Walk the talk. (2-3 hours)										
"Participate  in  the  debate,  but  look  where  are  you  going.  Watch  out  for  the"										
physical obstacles while debating. For example we have given one topic to two teams they have pick up chits that who will speak for the motion or against. And both the teams have to together(commonly) pick up one more chit which will decide the physical event that both of them will be performing while debating like dribbling ball on cricket bat. More they lose balance more the marks are reduced										
&their points should be relevant.										
Judging   criteria:The    more       Number   of    misbalances’   the   more   marks										
"detucted,Relevant points & views on the topic"										
"Requirements: White paper, bats (6),ball(6),badminton(6),shuttle cock."										
Place: Empty classroom/ground/clear space										
Make them dribble and make them walk on a infinite shaped path										
Round 3: Liar Liar (tentatively 1-2 hours)										
Just to make sure of your win or to create problem for your opponent you will										
"have to hide all the proofs and witnesses that are helpful for them, then you have to go through the same obstacle, and reach court on time to present your case. But each proof will have its different significance For example let’s say there is a"										
murder; two suspects and their respective lawyers. They have to prove that their										
client was not present at the time of crime. So the proof is an atm slip of a place										
entirely opposite to that of murder scene and also a cctv footage of that person in the atm at that time .Now the atm slip will have 5 points and the cctv footage which a more strong proof have 10 points. So totaling many points from many such proofs we will declare the winner. Now if we give them 2.5 hours: One hour for hiding the clues of opponent team and another hour to find their own clue										
.And last .5 hour to rush to court and present your case.										
"Judging criteria: Number of clues, Obstacles created, Courtroom presentation,"										
Time management.										
"Requirements: Paper, pens, lawyer coat, plastic colored sheets, tape, fevicol."										
"Place: Ground/classroom, classroom"										
BACKUPS-										
1st round:										
Story Player:										
"the 1st round will test the participants on their level of thinking, spontaneity and"										
"the way of expression. They will be showed a crime scene or a story with missing sequences relating to a murder case for a limited amount of time,say 50 sec.They will have to make up the story by themselves and tell it without any pause in 30- 40 sec by focussing on a board of sign showing infinity.they would be judged on"										
the basis of the time they take to complete the task.										
requirements:-										
"laptops,mobile,chart paper,sketch pens,colors"										
Round 2										
TALK SENSE										
In this round one of the team mate would be blind folded and asked to sense the										
"objects given by touch but he cannot speak and see so he will have to enact it to his team mate.Now in the conduction of this event,one of the volunteer will take one of the team mate to a side,Blind-fold him and make him touch objects given in the sack/bag.He then would enact it to his team member who will not only have to judge it but also by judging it right(if he judges it right),write a story based on the given objects guessed.He will pen down his guesses so that there is no chance of any signal or communication by any chance between the two team"										
members.										
Judging criteria:										
First judged on the acting ability of one team mate:10-20 cent										
Second is on the correct guessing : each object carries 20 weightage										
"1 guessed right ,2 wrong:20 on 60 and so on."										
Third is on the story writing and creativity:20-30 cent										
"If suppose a person guesses all wrong ,but story is write then he will get marks"										
based on story and acting only.										
The division of marks will make it less probable that there is a tie.Even if there is a										
tie then the story with most marks(30) will be given preference.										
ROUND 3										
(WILD-CARD)										
"For  adding  a  suspense  element,  we  will  have  a  wild  card.It  can  be  a  Group"										
discussion  on  various  youth  related  topics  or  on  crimes/murder/interesting mystery conditions.										
"As this round is a wild card, so in this we are giving the liberty to get entry back"										
"directly to the finale just by G.D. Only those are eligible who were eliminated in the second round.If 4 teams are in the finale then we carry forward 2 more so that we make them play against each other. So total of 6  teams go in final round.In final round 6 teams with 3 set of 2 each playing for 1,2 and 3rd place.The 3 sets are divided based on their previous rounds performance.But the 2 teams playing against each other for second or third position can overcome those who are playing for 1st position if they do exceptionally well in the Finale round and beat the ones who are leading.Scores will be made known (if at all ) only at the"										
end of the event.										
Requirements:										
Sacks or opaque polybags to keep the objects										
Objects will be decided at later stage.										
Pens and papers										
"For G.D.: Moderators , a room"										
ROUND 4										
WHO IS WHO?										
Two teams will be taking part simultaneously in this round.										
A mystery has to be solved by them.										
To solve the mystery a team requires at least 3 clues. But each team will be given										
2 clues only.										
Both teams should try to solve the mystery with the clues given to them. This										
"round proceeds in such a way that both the teams will be listening to each other’s view on the mystery and in meanwhile the teams will be using the clues given to them. As described a team should require about minimum 3 clues, so while a team solving a mystery when they use the clue the other team gets to know the"										
clue and the other team can use it solve the mystery.										
The other team should identify the clue from other team discussion and solve the										
mystery. The team may be misguided by taking up lead on thing which is not a clue or the first team might be bluffing to get to know the clue from that team or										
solely for the purpose to misguide the other team.										
The thing a team should be able to solve the mystery										
Judging criteria:										
Judges will be listening to the arguments and discussions and judging will be done										
according to the skills of parcipants .										
PUBLICITY:										
"1.  Help  desk  in  java,hostels.And  organaising  mini  games  to  make  people"										
interested.										
2Class room to class room publicity										
3 In java telling food vendors to hand over events poster to students										
"4 Posters near famous eating places in java/food court,atm,notice boards,water"										
coolers.										
5 Publicity through social media										
Suggestions about Aaruush 15’										
1. 100 hrs aaruush.										
2More informative workshops										
3Inviting more colleges to attend the fest										
4Mascot for Aaaruush.										
Coordinators-										
Vaishali        ECE    2year 1041310410           mishraarchana319@gmail.com										
9003239270										
Humsheer    ECE    2year 1041310383           Hstar30@gmail.com										
08608554763										
CO-Coordinators										
Priyanka       ECE    2year 1041310376           r6priyanka96@gmail.com               ---										
9962642014										
Paramkusham Sai Ritvik  IT        2year 1081310074										
ritvik.sunrises@gmail.com         8056283017										
Youth parliament										
INTRODUCTION										
"In this event, the students are given a chance to face a parliamentary situation."										
"The participants will have to present their views on the technical, social and economic issues."										
Problem statement:										
The  participant must fill an online form  and  pass the online  test attached with  the  form.  The										
screened candidates need to pass the JAM round to enter the final round.										
Event description:										
Round 1: Online form cum test (subjective test related to current affairs)										
Round 2: JAM session where each participants will be given a topic and he/she										
must speak about it for a minute.										
Round  3:  (Final  Round)  The  finalized  participants  shall  go  into  the  parliamentary  round  where										
"technical, social and economic issues shall be discussed."										
Rules:										
1.   Only participants who have filled the online form are eligible for the JAM session.										
2.    In JAM session the candidate must not digress from the given topic. Mere definition of the topic would not be considered.										
3.   Appropriateness of the stated point to the topic would be given consideration.										
Unruly behaviour during the parliamentary round shall not be tolerated.										
JUDGING CRITERIA										
# Based upon the appropriateness of the topic in the JAM session.										
# Final decisions would be made by the judges.										
FAQs										
Q. Is this a team event?										
"A. No, a single participant is allowed."										
Q. What type of topics could be in JAM session?										
A. For example: should there be quotas in college?										
Contact details:										
"•    Suchasmita Acharjee: 09600198925, suchasmitaacharjee@gmail.com,"										
"•    Tanmay Jowhar: 09566052307, tanmayjohar@gmail.com,"										
"•    Anisha Biswas: 09789938645, 2511.ani@gmail.com."										
